Jeremy Li

www.jeremyli.space

jeremyli.0623@gmail.com

Tel: (781)-605-7163 39 Florence St, Boston, MA

Objective

A software engineer also can get hooked on product. Couple years software engineering experiences not only bolster my technical capability but nurture product visions and business acumen. I have a very strong focus on product usability in the work and love to take actions on digging feature insights. I desire to launch captivated products that can help our customer be successful. Will learn whatever is needed to bring values on my team.

Work Experiences

Microsoft Crop, Bellevue Square, WA

Software Engineer, Microsoft Teams

Jun, 2020 - Now

• Primarily working on MWT (Modern Work Transformation) targeting product line to increase MS Teams application's rich interactions with users, helps targeting gain higher MAU goal by achieving 600K from 450K.

Veracode, Inc, Burlington, MA

Software Engineer, Developer Integration

Mar, 2018 – May, 2019

As being engineer,

- Built friction-less third-party plugins/toolings to support user-friendly security customer community.
- Scaled Jira standalone server over AWS cloud-based ecosystem to reduce massive single point failures and refined technical requirements with team and achieved existing user's conversion rate from nothing to 21%.
- Worked on mitigating security risks by triaging security attacks and internal data compliance vulnerabilities.

As being PM side role,

- Built up customer metrics via SumoLogic pipeline to track real-time API calling through the entire integration eco-system (7 product lines), facilitate Sr. management and partnership to make strategic decisions.
- Involved proactively in Agile Scrum and DevOps process (A/B testing, canary releases) to enable fully CI/CD pipeline, gained better product sense and SaaS enterprise insights.
- Gathered customer feedback (Webex/Email/On-site) and refined user persona for integration features.
- Collaborate with designers and engineers to be a liaison for cross-functional process and development.

CA Technologies, Burlington, MA (Acuqired Veracode in Nov, 2017)

Software Engineer, Developer Integration

Nov, 2017 – Mar, 2018

• Implement and maintain a range of plugins/extensions of SaaS application security scan platform, led to increase at least 20% efficiency of proceeding application security scanning assessment.

Associate Software Engineer, Core Platform

Jun, 2016 – Nov,2017

- Tackled customer-faced technical problems and refactored the deprecated codebase.
- Launched visual studio extension into Microsoft Marketplace and got 6000+ downloads in 3 months.
- Been UX council member dedicated to my team, to unify and adopt best practice of front-end engineering.

Philips of North America, New York

Software Research Intern, Acute Care Solution

Sep – Dec, 2014

Processed, transformed large-scale healthcare dataset that can be later used for EMR research purposes.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, JavaScript/ES6, C#, Python, HTML5/CSS(Sass/LESS)
Web Framework: React, D3.js, .NET Core, Bootstrap, Gradle, Gulp, REST
Certification: PSM I (Professional Scrum Master). Google Analytics IO

Education

Northeastern University, College of Engineering, Boston, MA

M.S. in Information Systems

Sep, 2015

Related Course: Application Engineering, Web Development, Advanced Data Science, Organization Mgt.

Central South University, College of Engineering, China

B.S. in Computational Material Engineering

Jun, 2013

Awards: 2nd prize in Challenge Cup Innovative Technology; "Most Influential Member", Engineer-Club. Leadership: College Vice-President of Innovation and Entrepreneurship Association.

Academic Projects

U.S. Airlines On-Time Performance Analytics Project

Cleaned, transformed large-scale datasets from RITA, visualized on-time performance as graphs and charts.